Sanghee Kim

sangheestyle@gmail.com • +1 (917) 565-6417 • New York, NY https://stackoverflow.com/users/568901/sangheestyle • https://github.com/sangheestyle

Summary

I enjoy identifying root problems of the company and grasping how to solve them. I am a fast learner and has a strong interest on the evolution of technology.

My area of interest is how to combine data and provide it through the web to make people access information easier and understand what they have. I have worked at both startups and large corporations, however I find that regardless of the company size my natural communication ability allows me to speak with equal ease to everyone from upper management to remote engineers.

Employment

Software Engineer, dMetrics Inc.

Sep 2015 - Present, New York, NY

- Python, ElasticSearch, AWS Lambda and APIG based on serverless framework.
- Migrated web API based on Python Django to AWS Lambda. Improvements in search API led to better concurrency reducing end user latency as well as costs.
- Development on Django web app with Elasticsearch. Improvements in algorithms led to 3x faster response time and dramatic efficiencies in production resource requirements.
- Development on ETL pipeline for pharmaceutical data processing with Neo4j and Scrapy (Python).

Research Assistant, Univ of Colorado, Boulder

Jan 2014 - May 2015, Boulder, CO

- DARPA MUSE: developed a crawler and analyzer for feeding data of projects hosted at GitHub into Big Data infrastructures in the project. (Node.js, Python, MongoDB, Cassandra)
- DARPA APAC: analyzed similarity among documents such as android app descriptions from Google Play and classified them in the project (Python, Lucene)

Research Engineer, MC Lab in LG Electronics.

Feb 2005 - Feb 2012, Seoul, South Korea

- As a startup member within LG, designed and implemented LG Android Projects, which is a collaboration system utilized for developing Android devices and facilitating software developments by software tools. Git, Gerrit, Doku wiki, and Jenkins were used. Became a crucial part of the parent company. (Nov 2009 Feb 2012)
- Maintained process and source codes of GM730 (Windows Mobile Platform), Symbian/S60 based projects.
- Ported SyncML and OMA DRM into Symbian/S60 mobile devices developed in C++. (Jun 2005 Nov 2009)

Education

University of Colorado, Boulder

2013 - 2015, Boulder, CO

M.S. in Computer Science, speciality in Data Science Advisor: Tom Yeh

Inha University

2003 - 2004, Incheon, South Korea

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering Transferred from Seokyeong University

Skills

- Programming language: Python, Javascript (C++, Java, Perl)
- DB: Elasticsearch, DynamoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Neo4j.
- Git(Lecturer experience), AWS ecosystem (mostly Lambda, APIG, RDS), Serverless framework, JIRA, Scrapy.

Natural languages: English (fluent), Korean (native)